remote.com 2018-02-09

# Privacy Policy | Remote.com Help Center

1\.     General

We at Remote.com, Inc., d/b/a Remote.com (“we,” “our” or “us”) very much respect your privacy, are committed to protecting it and want you to be informed about the ways we protect, use and share the information that we collect.

This Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) serves to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of the information we receive when you visit the website and associated domains of [http://www.remote.com](http://www.remote.com/) (the “Site”) and when you access use any part of our services, software, applications, content, programs and products available through the Site or other related toolbars, widgets, applications or distribution channels operated by us (the “Services”).  This Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through the Site or the Services, when you access or use any content appearing on the Site or made available through the Services, or that we collect on your behalf as part of the Services.

This Policy is an integral part of our[ Terms of Service](http://branded.me/terms) (the “Terms of Service”).

IMPORTANT – TRANSFER OF DATA AND PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE U.S.

WE PRIMARILY STORE DATA ABOUT YOU, INCLUDING PERSONAL INFORMATION, ON SERVERS LOCATED AND OPERATED WITHIN THE UNITED STATES. THEREFORE, IF YOU RESIDE OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES, IN ORDER TO PROVIDE THE SERVICES TO YOU, WE MAY SEND AND STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION (ALSO COMMONLY REFERRED TO AS PERSONAL DATA) OUTSIDE OF THE COUNTRY WHERE YOU RESIDE OR ARE LOCATED, TO THE UNITED STATES. THEREFORE, OUR COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IS SUBJECT TO THE UNITED STATES’ LAWS RELATED TO PRIVACY AND USE OF PERSONAL DATA AND INFORMATION.  THESE LAWS, INCLUDING WHAT IS DETERMINED TO BE “PERSONAL DATA AND/OR INFORMATION,” ARE DIFFERENT AND MAY BE LESS PROTECTIVE THAN THOSE APPLICABLE TO YOU IN YOUR COUNTRY OF RESIDENCE. BY ACCEPTING THE TERMS OF THIS POLICY YOU ACKNOWLEDGE, AGREE AND CONSENT TO (1) THE TRANSFER TO AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION ON SERVERS LOCATED OUTSIDE OF THE COUNTRY WHERE YOU RESIDE, (2) OUR COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AS DESCRIBED HEREIN AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE LAWS OF THE UNITED STATES THAT MAY BE DIFFERENT AND MAY BE LESS PROTECTIVE THAN THOSE IN YOUR COUNTRY AND (3) THAT YOU ARE TAKING A RISK BY USING THE SITE AND SERVICES.

Changes to this Policy.

We reserve the right, at its sole and absolute discretion, to change, modify, add to, supplement or delete any of the terms and conditions of this Policy by posting an updated version to the Site. You should visit this page periodically to review the most current Policy, because it is binding on you. We will endeavor to notify you of material changes by email, but will not be liable for any failure to do so. If any future changes to this Policy are unacceptable to you or cause you to no longer be in compliance with this Policy, you must terminate, and immediately stop using, the Services. Your continued use of the Services following any revision to this Policy constitutes your complete and irrevocable acceptance of any and all such changes.

2\.     Types of Information We Collect

Personal Identifiable Information “PII”

Personal Identifiable Information is information that specifically identifies you as an individual, including, but not limited to: your name, your mailing address, your telephone number, your mobile number, your email address, your date of birth, your credit card or other billing information, your account login information for third party services providers or your company’s name (“PII”).  In order to use the Services and create an account on the Site (your “Account”), you must provide us with at least your name and email address, and a password for your Account.  In the course of using the Services, you may choose to provide additional PII on your profile to create your professional profile, network with other users, administer your Account, or access certain restricted parts of the Site and the Services.  Providing additional PII also enables us to provide you with relevant contents on and off of the Services.  You understand that by creating an Account with us, we and other users or visitors of the Site will be able to identify you by your profile. We may also ask for your credit card details if you purchase paid Services.

You may import your address books, contact lists and/or emails, including first name, last name, email address, company, job title and other Personal Information of your contacts (collectively, “Contact Data”), into the Service. You may choose to activate or deactivate the import feature on your Account at any time. When this feature is activated, your address book, contact list or email is copied to our servers and automatically scanned for relevant Contact Data. For some email services, you may need to provide your username and password for us to access your email to enable this feature. We store the Contact Data and use it to provide the services and help you manage and network with your contacts in connection with the Services as described further below. We use industry-standard security practices for the security of any username and or password you provide us.

Non- PII

We also collect information about the use of our Service and the characteristics and activities of users of the Services, from which any personal information has been removed (“Non-Personal Identifiable Information”). When you access the Site or use the Services, we may collect Non-PII, including without limitation:

  * Information regarding your use of the Services, including without limitation, activity and visit behavior on your website;
  * Information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website or online service (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include, but is not limited to: your computer's Internet Protocol (IP) address, device type, browser type, operating system and version, the web page you were visiting before you came to the Site, information you search for on the Site, locale preferences, identification numbers associated with your devices, your mobile carrier, date and time stamps associated with transactions, system configuration information, metadata concerning your files, and other interactions with the Services;
  * Your website alias, website URL;
  * If you make or enable a transaction such as a purchase directly from our Site, we will collect billing and financial information as necessary to process your charges, which may include your postal and email addresses; and
  * Content that you upload to your Account, your website, your profile or otherwise provided to us that is not Personal Information.

In this Policy, we refer to all information collected from or about you, including but not limited to Personal Information, Contact Data and Non-Personal Information, as “Your Information.”

Cookies.

Cookies are small bits of information that this website places on your computer. We and our third party service providers use cookies and Pixel Tags to identify your IP address, browser type, domain name, and specific web pages through which you click. This data is collected automatically and utilized to help us look for trends to improve our website and your interactive experience. The cookies allow us to recognize you when you return to the website and to provide you with a customized experience that we feel will be of value to you. The cookies that are configured by this website do not contain any personally identifying information, such as your name, or sensitive information, such as your credit card number. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the website you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the Services

Social Media.

The Services provide you and users the opportunity to interact and post content through various social media sites including, but not limited to, Facebook and Twitter (“Social Media”). Your interactions with the Social Media sites and any information you provide to us in connection with such interactions are not Personal Information.  Our Site may also include social media features, such as the Facebook button, and widgets, such as the Share this button, or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site (the “Features”). These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Features to function properly. The Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Service Providers.

We collect the information about you and other individuals (including those in your Contact Data) from the following third party sources: (a) third parties who license, sell or otherwise provide data they have collected (“Third Party Data”); or (b) publicly available sources, such as via the Internet and social networks, including through public or licensed APIs (“Public Data”).  Furthermore, as part of the Services, we may combine Your Information with Third Party Data and/or Public Data to create more complete data records regarding your contacts.  In order to do so, we may share Your Information with our third party service providers to make data associations between your Contact Data and Third Party Data and/or Public Data.  We do not sell your Personal Information or Contact Data to any third party; however, we may share Your Information with third parties as described below.

Additional Features.

We are always seeking to improve the Services and will introduce new features, some of which may result in the collection of new information. Furthermore, new partnerships or corporate transactions may result in new features, and we may potentially collect new types of information. If we start collecting substantially new types of personal information and materially change how we handle your data, we will modify this Policy and post the revised Policy on the Site and may notify you in accordance with this Policy.

3\.     How We Use Your Information

Your Information, including your Contact Data, that you provide to us may reveal or allow others to identify aspects of your life and your contacts’ life that are not expressly stated on your profile (for example, your picture or your name may reveal your gender). By providing Your Information to us, you are expressly and voluntarily accepting the Terms of Service and freely accepting and agreeing to our processing of Your Information, including your Contact Data, in ways set out by this Policy. Supplying to us any information deemed “sensitive” by applicable law is entirely voluntary on your part.

When you submit information to us, it is collected, processed and maintained solely by us or by third party agents who are bound by privacy restrictions at least as restrictive as those set forth in this Policy. Your Information is used and disclosed for, but is not limited to, the following purposes: (i) to provide the Services, including without limitation to collect payment for paid features, (ii) to administer your use of the Services and any accounts you may have with us, (iii) to personalize your experience, (iv) to provide to you Service announcements, (v) to provide you with further information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting, such as newsletters, marketing or promotional materials, (vi) on behalf of and according to instructions of a third party, such as our advertising partners, (vii) to enforce our Terms of Service, (viii) to resolve any disputes between users of the Site or between such users and us, and (ix) to contact you to obtain feedback from you regarding the Site and the Services.  If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such contact, announcements, information or offers, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in the communication.  Furthermore, communications that you initiate through the Services (for example, an invitation sent to a non-user or non-member) will list your name and primary email address in the header of the message.

We use Non-Personal Information for the above purposes and in addition in order to (i) monitor and analyze use of the Services and for the technical administration of the Site, (ii) improve the Site and the Services, (iii) generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics and website use behavior of our users, and (iv) verify that users of the Services meet the criteria required to process their requests.

Analytics Information.

We use third-party analytics tools (such as Google Analytics) to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Services. These tools collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including the web pages you visit, your browser add-ons, and other information that assists us in improving the Services. We may collect and use this analytics information together with your Personal Information and stitch together session data from unauthenticated user visits with authenticated user visits to build a broader profile of our individual users so that we can serve you better.  You can find out more information about how Google Analytics works and collects and processes the data here: [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

Site Specific Services.

We may post additional ancillary privacy notices with respect to specific services.

Links to Other Websites.

We may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed.

This Policy applies only to the Site and the Services. We do not exercise control over third party services or other websites that provide information, or over banners, other advertisements or links from within the Site or the Services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer’s browser, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other websites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the Personal Information that you submit, and the collection and use of such information and access of any third party websites are subject to such third party’s privacy policy. We encourage you to read the privacy policies and other terms of such third parties' websites before using their services.

4\.     Information Sharing and Disclosure

Disclosure by You of Information of Other Users.

The sending of unwanted messages from one user to another is strictly forbidden. Personal Information of another user obtained through your use of the Site or the Services may be used by you only for the purpose for which such Personal Information was provided to you and strictly in accordance with the Terms of Service and this Policy, or otherwise subject to such user’s prior written consent.

Your Submissions.

As a professional profile and networking platform, part of Your Information, including without limitation content of your profile, is published to the public Internet and visible to unregistered visitors to the Site.  This public profile will be indexed and displayed through public search engines when someone searches for your name.  Further, nothing shall restrict our right to use, access, process, collect, disclose, share or distribute any Public Data, even if such Public Data is duplicative of your Contact Data.

Any information you choose to provide in a comment or a submission on the Site or the Services will be publicly available and should reflect how much you want other users to know about you. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information and we encourage you to think carefully about what information about yourself you disclose in your comments or submissions. If you disclose your Personal Information to others, whether or not they are users of the Site, on our Site or through the Services or otherwise, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them.

Social Media.

If you have opted to link your Account to your Social Media account, you can easily share content from the Services to these third party services, in accordance with your Account settings (which you may change at any time) and respective policies of these third parties.  If you connect your Account with one of these services, you may be giving such third party service access to your Personal Information or Contact Data.

Service Providers.

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate or enhance the Services (for example, we share parts of Your Information with service providers in order to facilitate data associations and to create a more complete data record of your contacts), to provide the Services on our behalf (such as payment processing), to assist us in analyzing how the Services is used, and to perform services related to administration of the Services or the Site (including, without limitation, maintenance, payments, hosting and database management services, website analytics and administration).  We may share Your Information, including your Personal Information and Content Data, with such third party service providers, so that they may perform these tasks on our behalf. While these third party service providers may not sell Your Information, they may use Your Information, including your Contact Data, to make associations between data elements that constitute Public Data (e.g., email address, twitter handle or Facebook username) and disclose these data elements to their end users even if the association was previously undisclosed. For example, if a person has a twitter handle, an email address and a Facebook page, all of which constitute Public Data, and the part of Your Information shared with them includes the data association to tie those three elements of Public Data together, such third party may disclose that connection. They are obligated to comply with this Policy and may not use Your Information for any other purpose.

Non-Personal Identifiable Information and Aggregate Information.

We may, from time to time, share Non-Personal Identifiable Information and/or aggregated information. The Non-PII that we share may include, but not be limited to: website URL, date of site built, site category type, user category type, performance data, reports generated as a result of your use of the Services that includes non-identifying information, and other Log Data. This shared information may be used for industry analysis, demographic profiling, other commercial purposes and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services. Any information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.

Combined Information.

We may combine certain Personal Identifiable Information with Non-Personal Identifiable Information in order to allow us to create information packages and services that are better tailored to your interests and preferences. Among other things, linking this information may allow us generally to improve and personalize the Site and the Services. If we combine or link any information with your Personal Information, the resulting combination will be treated as Personal Information under this Policy.

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement.

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to: (1) comply with a legal requirement or process, including, but not limited to, civil and criminal subpoenas, court orders or other compulsory disclosures; (2) enforce this Policy or the Terms of Service; (3) respond to claims of a violation of the rights of third parties; (4) respond to user comments or service inquiries; (5) protect the our rights, property, or safety and the rights, property and safety of the Services, our users or the public; or (6) prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical, inappropriate or legally actionable.

Business Transfers.

We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including among others your Personal Information, Contact Data, Non-Personal Information and Log Data, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of all or substantially all of our shares or assets, or in the event of our bankruptcy.

We encourage you to consider carefully what information to share as part of your Account profile and elsewhere in the Services, and we recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information. Any information you choose to share should reflect how much you want other users of the Services and the public to know about you. You can review and revise your Account profile information at any time.

5\.     Changing or Deleting Your Information

You may review, update, correct or delete Your Information, if not required to be retained by law or for legitimate business reasons. If you wish to delete your Account, you must contact us at [support@remote.com](mailto:support@remote.com).

Canadian Visitors to the Site.

Canadian citizens, except under circumstances defined by law, are entitled to access their own Personal Information collected by us by contacting us at [support@remote.com.](mailto:support@remote.com) We may ask you to pay an administrative fee for accessing or copying your Personal Information, but will inform you of the anticipated charges and confirm that you want us to proceed before processing your request. If you believe that the Personal Information about you that we have collected is incomplete or inaccurate, we will correct the information upon verification of the omission or error and of the identity of the person requesting the change. If you wish additional information about our Personal Information management, to access, correct or have us investigate any matters in relation to your Personal Information, please contact us.

California Residents.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 requires certain businesses that share customer personal information with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses’ practices related to such information-sharing. We currently do not share or disclose your Personal Information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  If we change our practices in the future, we will implement an opt-out policy as required under California laws.

6\.     Our Policy Toward Children

We understand the importance of protecting children’s privacy, especially in an online environment. The Site and Services are not designed for or directed at children and children under 13 are not permitted to use the Services. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13.  If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.  If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [support@remote.com](mailto:support@remote.com).

7\.     Security

[Remote.com](http://remote.com/) is very concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. However, we cannot guarantee unauthorized personnel will not gain access to your personal information despite our efforts. You should note that in using Remote.com, your information would travel through third party infrastructures, which are not under our control. PLEASE DO NOT PROVIDE ANY PRIVILEGED INFORMATION ON THE SITE OR WHEN USING THE SERVICE.

If you receive an email asking you to update your Personal Information, do not reply and please contact us at [support@remote.com](mailto:support@remote.com).

8\.     Contacting Us

If you have any concerns or questions about this Policy, please contact us at [support@remote.com](mailto:support@remote.com).
